A girl I've never met before
فتاة لم أقابلها من قبل
changed my life and the life of thousands of other people.
غيرت حياتي وحياة الآلاف من الأشخاص.
I'm the CEO of DoSomething.org.
أنا المديرة التنفيذية لمنظمة DoSomething.org.
It's one of the largest organizations in the world for young people.
هي واحدة من أكبر المنظمات في العالم للشباب.
In fact it's bigger than the Boy Scouts in the United States.
في الحقيقة هي أكبر من "بوي سكوتس" في أمريكا.
And we're not homophobic.
ونحن لسنا ضد المثلية الجنسية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And it's true -- the way we communicate with young people is by text,
و صحيح - أن طريقتنا للتواصل مع الشباب تكون بالرسائل النصية،
because that's how young people communicate.
لأن هذه هي الطريقة التي يتواصل بها الشباب.
So we'll run over 200 campaigns this year,
لذلك سنقوم بتنظيم 200 حملة هذه السنة،
things like collecting peanut butter for food pantries,
حملات مثل جمع زبدة الفول السوداني لمخازن الطعام،
or making Valentine's Day cards for senior citizens who are homebound.
أو إعداد بطاقات عيد الحب لكبار السن الذين يُلازمون بيوتهم.
And we'll text them.
وسوف نرسل لهم رسائل نصية.
And we'll have a 97 percent open rate.
وسوف نتحصل على معدل 97%.
It'll over-index Hispanic and urban.
وسيشمل بتوسع الإسباني والمتمدن.
We collected 200,000 jars of peanut butter
لقد جمعنا 200000 جرة من زبدة الفول السوداني
and over 365,000 Valentine's Day cards.
وأكثر من 365000 بطاقة عيد الحب.
This is big scale. OK --
هذا كثير جدا. حسنا --
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
But there's one weird side effect.
ولكن هناك أثر جانبي غريب.
Every time we send out a text message,
كل مرة نرسل فيها رسالة نصية،
we get back a few dozen text messages having nothing to do with peanut butter
نستقبل العشرات من الرسائل التي ليست لها أي علاقة مع زبدة الفول السوداني
or hunger or senior citizens --
أو الجوع أو المواطنين كبار السن --
but text messages about being bullied,
ولكن رسائل نصية حول تعرضهم للمعاملة القاسية،
text messages about being addicted to pot.
رسائل نصية حول إدمانهم الماريجوانا.
And the worst message we ever got said exactly this:
وأسوء رسالة استقبلناها على الإطلاق هي التالية:
"He won't stop raping me.
"إنه لا يكف عن اغتصابي.
It's my dad.
إنه أبي.
He told me not to tell anyone. Are you there?"
لقد قال لي لا تخبري أحدا. هل أنتم هنا؟ "
We couldn't believe this was happening.
لم نستطع أن نُصدّق أن هذا يحدث.
We couldn't believe that something so horrific could happen to a human being,
لم نصدق بأن شيئا بهذه البشاعة يمكن أن يحدث للإنسان،
and that she would share it with us -- something so intimate, so personal.
وأنها ستشاركنا إياه -- شيئ شخصي جدا.
And we realized we had to stop triaging this
ولقد قررنا بأنه يجب علينا إيقاف ذلك
and we had to build a crisis text line for these people in pain.
وعلينا تخصيص مكان لهؤلاء الأشخاص الذين يُعانون
So we launched Crisis Text Line,
لكتابة رسائلهم وبالفعل أطلقنا خط الأزمة،
very quietly, in Chicago and El Paso -- just a few thousand people in each market.
بهدوء شديد، في شيكاغو وأل باسو -- فقط آلاف من الأشخاص في كل سوق.
And in four months, we were in all 295 area codes in America.
وفي ظرف 4 أشهر، كنا في جميع نطاقات 295 منطقة بأمريكا.
Just to put that into perspective,
فقط لوضع هذا ضمن زاوية معينة،
that's zero marketing and faster growth than when Facebook first launched.
لم يتم تسويق هذا ولقد نما بسرعة مقارنة بإطلاق الفايسبوك.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Text is unbelievably private.
النص خاص بشكل لا يُصدّق.
No one hears you talking.
لا أحد يسمعك تتحدّث.
So we spike everyday at lunch time --
ويرتفع الحجم كل يوم في وقت الغداء.
kids are sitting at the lunch table
يجلس الأطفال إلى طاولة الغداء
and you think that she's texting the cute boy across the hall,
وتعتقد أنها ترسل رسالة نصية للطفل اللطيف بالبهو،
but she's actually texting us about her bulimia.
ولكنها في الحقيقة ترسل لنا رسالة حول مرض الشره لديها.
And we don't get the word "like" or "um" or hyperventilating or crying.
ولم نستقبل كلمة مثل "أحب" أو "هممم" أو اللهاث أو البكاء.
We just get facts.
ولكن نحصل على حقائق.
We get things like, "I want to die.
نستقبل عبارات مثل، "أريد أن أموت.
I have a bottle of pills on the desk in front of me."
لدي علبة من الحبوب أمامي على المكتب."
And so the crisis counselor says,
ويجيب مستشار الأزمة كما يلي،
"How about you put those pills in the drawer while we text?"
"ماذا لو وضعت تلك العلبة في الدرج بينما نتحدث؟"
And they go back and forth for a while.
ويتواصلون بالرسائل النصية لمدة.
And the crisis counselor gets the girl to give her her address,
ويطلب مستشار الأزمة من الفتاة أن تعطيه عنوانها،
because if you're texting a text line, you want help.
لأنك لو أرسلت رسالة نصية فإنك بالتأكيد تريد المساعدة.
So she gets the address
تحصلت على العنوان
and the counselor triggers an active rescue
وانشغل المستشار ببعث عملية الإنقاذ
while they're texting back and forth.
بينما كانوا يرسلون الرسائل النصية.
And then it goes quiet --
ثم ساد هدوء رهيب --
23 minutes with no response from this girl.
23 دقيقة من دون تلقي أي إجابة من الفتاة.
And the next message that comes in says --
و الرسائل النصية التي تلقيناها كانت --
it's the mom --
إنها الأم --
"I had no idea, and I was in the house,
"لم تكن لدي أدنى فكرة، ولقد كنت موجودة بالمنزل،
we're in an ambulance on our way to the hospital."
نحن في سيارة الإسعاف في طريقنا إلى المستشفى."
As a mom that one just --
كأم تلك المرة --
The next message comes a month later.
تلقينا رسائل نصية بعد شهر.
"I just got out of the hospital.
"لقد خرجت من المستشفى.
I was diagnosed as bipolar, and I think I'm going to be OK."
وتم تشخيصي بالهوس الاكتئابي، وأعتقد أنني سأكون على ما يرام."
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I would love to tell you that that's an unusual exchange,
أود أن أخبركم أن ذلك كان تغييرا غير عادي،
but we're doing on average 2.41 active rescues a day.
ولكننا نقوم بمعدل 2.41 من الإنقاذ في اليوم.
Thirty percent of our text messages are about suicide and depression -- huge.
30% من الرسائل النصية تتمحور حول الانتحار والاكتئاب -- هذا ضخم.
The beautiful thing about Crisis Text Line
الرائع بخصوص خط الرسائل ذات الصلة بالأزمة
is that these are strangers counseling other strangers
أن هناك غرباء يُواسون غرباء آخرين
on the most intimate issues,
حول أكثر المشاكل حميمية،
and getting them from hot moments to cold moments.
لإخراجهم من اللحظات الصعبة وتهدئتهم.
It's exciting, and I will tell you
هذا مثير، وسأُخبركم بأن لدينا
that we have done a total of more than 6.5 million text messages
ما يُقارب أكثر من 6.5 مليون رسالة نصية
in less than two years.
في أقل من سنتين.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
But the thing that really gets me hot and sweaty about this,
ولكن الشيء الوحيد الذي جعلني أشعر بالتعرق،
the thing that really gets me psyched is the data:
الشيء الذي يثير جنوني حقا هو البيانات:
6.5 million messages --
6.5 مليون رسالة نصية --
that's the volume, velocity and variety to provide a really juicy corpus.
هذا الحجم والسرعة والتنوع لتوفير مدوّنة جيّدة.
We can do things like predictive work.
يمكننا القيام بأشياء مثل العمل التنبؤي.
We can do all kinds of conclusions and learnings from that data set.
يمكننا القيام بكل أنواع الاستنتاجات والتعلم من خلال مجموعة البيانات.
So we can be better, and the world can be better.
يمكننا أن نكون أفضل، والعالم سيصبح أفضل.
So how do we use the data to make us better?
لكن كيف نستعمل البيانات لكي نصبح أفضل؟
Alright, chances are someone here, someone watching this
حسنا، الفرص هي شخص هنا، شخص يشاهد هذا
has seen a therapist or a shrink at some point in time in your life --
كان معالجا أو طبيبا نفسيا في وقت ما في حياتك --
you do not have to raise your hand.
ليس عليك أن ترفع يدك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
How do you know that person's any good?
كيف يمكنك معرفة أن شخصا ما جيد؟
Oh, they have a degree from Harvard on the wall?
أووه لديه شهادة من هارفرد معلقة على الحائط؟
Are you sure he didn't graduate in the bottom 10 percent?
هل أنت متأكد من أنه لم يتخرج من ضمن 10% في آخر القائمة؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
When my husband and I saw a marriage counselor,
عندما رأيت أنا وزوجي مستشارة الزواج،
I thought she was a genius when she said,
اعتقدت بأنها عبقرية عندما قالت،
"I'll see you guys in two weeks -- but I need to see you next week, sir."
"سأراكم معا في ظرف أسبوعين ولكن علي أن أقابلك بعد أسبوع سيدي"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We have the data to know what makes a great counselor.
لدينا البيانات التي تدلّنا على مستشار جيد.
We know that if you text the words "numbs" and "sleeve,"
نعلم أنك إذا أرسلت الكلمات "تخدّر" و "كُمّ"،
there's a 99 percent match for cutting.
هناك 99% بالقطع والتوقف.
We know that if you text in the words "mg" and "rubber band,"
ونعلم أنك إذا أرسلت الكلمات "ملغم" و"الشريط المطاطي"
there's a 99 percent match for substance abuse.
هناك 99% لتعاطي المخدرات.
And we know that if you text in "sex," "oral" and "Mormon,"
ونعلم أنك إذا أرسلت الكلمات "جنس" و"فم" و"المرمون"،
you're questioning if you're gay.
فأنت تشكك في كونك مثلي.
Now that's interesting information that a counselor could figure out
والآن هذه معلومات مهمة يمكن للمستشار معرفتها
but that algorithm in our hands means that an automatic pop-up says,
ولكن مجموعة القواعد التي في أيدينا تعني أن إجابة تلقائية هي:
"99 percent match for cutting -- try asking one of these questions"
"99% ترتبط بالقطع -- حاول طرح أحد هذه الأسئلة"
to prompt the counselor.
لتحثّ المستشار.
Or "99 percent match for substance abuse,
أو "99% تتعلق بتعاطي المخدرات،
here are three drug clinics near the texter."
وهاهي 3 عيادات للمدمنين على المخدرات قريبة من مرسلي الرسائل."
It makes us more accurate.
هذا يجعلنا أكثر دقة.
On the day that Robin Williams committed suicide,
في اليوم الذي انتحر فيه روبين وليامس،
people flooded hotlines all over this country.
شهدت الخطوط الساخنة ازدحاما في جميع أنحاء البلد.
It was sad to see an icon, a funnyman, commit suicide,
لقد كان من المحزن رؤية علما، كوميدي، انتحر،
and there were three hour wait times on every phone hotline in the country.
ولقد كان هناك انتظار لمدة 3 ساعات في كل خط ساخن في البلاد.
We had a spike in volume also.
كما ارتفع الحجم.
The difference was
الفرق كان
if you text us, "I want to die," or "I want to kill myself,"
إذا أرسلت لنا "أريد أن أموت" أو "أريد أن أقتل نفسي"،
the algorithm reads that, you're code orange,
النظام سيقرأ ذلك، وينسب إليك الرمز البرتقالي،
and you become number one in the queue.
وتصبح رقم 1 في قائمة الانتظار.
So we can handle severity, not chronological.
نحن نتعامل مع مستوى الشدة وليس الترتيب.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
This data is also making the world better
هذه البيانات تجعل العالم مكانا أفضل
because I'm sitting on the world's first map of real-time crises.
لأنني أُصنّف الأولى في خريطة العالم للأزمات الحقيقية.
Think about it:
فكروا في ذلك:
those 6.5 million messages, auto-tagging through natural language processes,
6.5 مليون رسالة يتم ترقيمها آليا باستخدام عمليات اللغة الطبيعية،
all of these data points --
كل هذه الحقائق --
I can tell you that the worst day of the week for eating disorders: Monday.
أستطيع أن أخبركم أن أسوأ يوم في الأسبوع لاضطرابات الأكل هو الاثنين.
The worst time of day for substance abuse: 5am.
أسوأ وقت في اليوم لتعاطي المخدرات هو الخامسة صباحا.
And that Montana is a beautiful place to visit
ومونتانا مكان جميل لزيارته
but you do not want to live there,
ولكنك لا تريد أن تعيش هناك،
because it is the number one state for suicidal ideation.
لأنها الولاية الأولى للتفكير في الانتحار.
And we've made this data public and free and open.
ولقد جعلنا هذه البيانات للعموم ومجانية.
We've pulled all the personally identifiable information.
لقد أزلنا كل المعلومات الشخصية.
And it's in a place called CrisisTrends.org.
وهو مكان يُدعى CrisisTrends.org
Because I want schools to be able to see
لأنني أريد من المسؤولين عن المدارس أن يعرفوا أن
that Monday is the worst day for eating disorders,
يوم الاثنين هو أسوأ يوم لاضطرابات الأكل،
so that they can plan meals
وذلك ليتمكنوا من التخطيط للوجبات
and guidance counselors to be there on Mondays.
وجلب مستشاري التوجيه ليكونوا بالمدرسة يوم الاثنين.
And I want families to see that substance abuse questions spike at 5am.
وأريد من العائلات أن تعرف أن أسئلة تعاطي المخدرات ترتفع عند 5 صباحا.
I want somebody to take care of those Native American reservations in Montana.
أريد شخصا ما أن يولي اهتماما لهذه المحافظات الأمريكية بمونتانا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Data, evidence
الحقائق، الأدلّة،
makes policy, research,
وضع السياسات، البحوث،
journalism, policing, school boards -- everything better.
الصحافة والشرطة والمدرسة -- كل شيء أفضل.
I don't think of myself as a mental health activist.
لا أفكر في نفسي كناشطة في مجال الصحة العقلية.
I think of myself as a national health activist.
وإنما أفكر في نفسي كناشطة وطنية في مجال الصحة العقلية.
I get really excited about this data, I'm a little nerdy.
أنا أتحمس حقا لهذه الحقائق، أنا مواظبة قليلا.
Yeah, that sounded too girly.
نعم، بدا هذا بناتي.
I'm nerdy.
أنا مهووسة بالعلم.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I love data.
أنا أحب الحقائق.
And the only difference really between me and those people in hoodies down the road
والفرق الوحيد بيني وبين هؤلاء الناس في آخر الشارع
with their fat-funded companies,
مع شركاتهم الممولة جيدا،
is that I'm not inspired by helping you find Chinese food at 2am in Dallas,
أنه لا يتم استلهامي بمساعدتك لتجد طعاما صينيا في دالاس عند 2 صباحا،
or helping you touch your wrist and get a car immediately,
أو مساعدتك على أن تلمس معصمك والحصول على سيارة فورا،
or swipe right and get laid.
أو السرقة بطريقة جيدة وممارسة الجنس.
I'm inspired --
لقد ألهمني ذلك --
(Laughter, applause)
(ضحك، تصفيق)
I want to use tech and data to make the world a better place.
أريد أن أستعمل التكنولوجيا والبيانات لجعل العالم مكانا أفضل.
I want to use it to help that girl,
أريد استعمال ذلك لمساعدة تلك الفتاة
who texted in about being raped by her father.
التي راسلتنا وأخبرتنا بأن والدها يغتصبها.
Because the truth is we never heard from her again.
لأننا في الحقيقة لم نسمع أي خبر عنها منذ تلك اللحظة.
And I hope that she is somewhere safe and healthy,
وأرجو أن تكون بمكان ما آمنة وفي صحة جيدة،
and I hope that she sees this talk
وآمل أن تشاهد هذه المحادثة
and she knows that her desperation
وأن تعلم أن يأسها
and her courage inspired the creation of Crisis Text Line
وشجاعتها قد ألهمانا لإنشاء خط مساعدة في حالة الأزمة
and inspires me every freaking day.
وألهمتني خلال كل يوم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)